Mesics, Emil, Papers /4091
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Emil Mesics Papers
1946-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Mesics, Emil
/4091
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
7984558
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 20, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 01, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4297: ILR School Biography Files
Mesics, Emil
7984558
- Wage, Salary and Cost of Living Documents, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Compensating Expatriates for the Cost of Living Abroad", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  National Industrial Conference Board Report.
- Harvard Business School Case Examples (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Attitude Survey (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 'An Inquiry into the Nature and Use of Authority" (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Glenn Gilman
- 'An Inquiry into the Nature and Use of Authority" Continued (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Documents on Automation, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Documents on Automation, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Automation: Boon or Bogeyman?", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  New York State Department of Labor
- Automation, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Automation, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Automation, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Xerox Corporation: A Case Study in Retraining", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  F F Foltman
- "Impact of Technological Change Upon Jobs and Labor Relations", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Delivered at the May 1956 Conference on Current Problems in Labor Relations and Arbitration, Cornell University
- "Expanded Training Opportunities for Out-of-School Youth" (Box 1, Folder 15)
  F. F. Foltman, M. K. Kohler
- Benefits Documents, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Benefits Documents, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Business Cycle (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "The GE Approach to Industrial Relations: A MAP Study", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  January 1962
- Collective Bargaining Documents, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "The Woodward Governor Approach to Industrial Relations: The Concept of the Corporate Partnership", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  A MAPI Study
- "Guide to College Recruiting Procedure", 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  January 4 1952
- Communication, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Conference Leadership, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  February 1951
- Conference leadership: Training Department Johnson & Johnson, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Conference Leadership, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  January 1951
- Manual for Developing Conference Leaders (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Industrial Relations Department, American Can Company
- "A Report of the Meetings on the Explanation and Discussion of a 'Management Conference Program'", 1951 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  September 22 and 23 1951
- Conference and Discussion Leadership, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Management Consultants (Box 1, Folder 30)
- "How to Delegate--Effectively", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Raymond Dreyfack
- Economics, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Economic Education, 1950-1962 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  April 1 1950 - August 1962
- Educational Principles and Training Manuals, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Lynn A Emerson
- Employee Personnel Records, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Employee Relations (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Employment, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- The Telford Classification Manual: How to Make and Use an Occupational Classification of the Positions in a Public or Commercial Organization, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Fred Telford. March 1 1937
- Employment, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Executives, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  July 1962 - September 15 1965
- Interview Development, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Labor Relations Accommodations, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- "Labor Turnover: Calculation and Cost", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Frederick J Gaudet, American Management Association
- "The Potential of Programmed Mechanical Devices as Aids in the Maintenance and Repair of Airborne Electronic Equipment" (Box 1, Folder 44)
  George H Foster
- Legislation: Training and Retraining, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Numeric Control Training, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Orientation: "Your Job with Otis" (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Performance Appraisals, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Personnel, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Personnel Administration, 1956-1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Personnel Function, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Personnel Research, 1958-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Personnel Salary Administration, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Policy Statements, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  December 1964
- Poverty, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Programmed Instruction, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Programmed Learning, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Remuneration, 1953-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Retirement Planning, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Retraining Older Workers, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- "On Preventing Conflicts of Interest in Government-Sponsored Research at Universities, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Safety, 1954-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Study Method, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Tests, 1947-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Tests, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  August 1966
- Training Evaluation, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  English and Spanish
- Unemployment Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Unions, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- The Proper Climate for Labor Relations, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Michigan State University. April 18 - 19 1962
- Vocational Education, 1952-1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Vocational Education, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Voluntary Education, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Voluntary Education, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Wages and Salary Transparencies, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Working Women, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Work, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Work Measurement, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- A Closer Look at Peer Ratings, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Adaptability of Older Workers to Technological Change (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Arnold S Tenenbaum and Gary Grenholm
- Administration of the Personnel Programs a Line Responsibility, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Paul L Mitzner. November and December 1960
- American Products Company "In Basket" Simulation, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- An Analysis of the Teaching Machine Field and Implications for Home Study Courses, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Winter 1961
- Analysis of the Training Director's Job, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Fall 1961
- A Note on Counseling Procedures (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Angelica's Purse (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Annotated Bibliography: The Hard-Core Unemployed (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Emil A Mesics
- An Overview of the Essentials of Management Development Programs (Box 3, Folder 10)
- An Uneasy Look at Performance Appraisal (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Douglas McGregor
- Assessing Management Talent, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Walter S Wikstrom. March 1967
- Appraisal and Interview: A Personal Approach to Management Development (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Harold Mayfield
- Westinghouse Lamp Division Apprentice Training Program, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Are Personnel Policies Different in a Non-Union Plant?, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Paul L Davis
- Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Case Incidents 561-565, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  January 6 1957 - May 21 1959
- Case Incident No. 8 Arbitrator's Decision Grievance 1416, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  February 13 1959
- Categories of Changes Expected to Result from Laboratory Training, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Check List for Orientation of New Employees Kemper Insurance, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Check Sheet for Starting New Employees on the Job, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- The Communication Process, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Comparison of Four Basic Systems of Job Evaluation, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Conference Leadership, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Coordination in Obtaining and Utilizing Manpower Data for Vocational-Technical Education Planning, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Edward B Jakubauskas. July 11 1968
- "Dear Lord", 1958 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  November 20 1958
- Definition of Job Evaluation, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- The Developing Revolution in Management Practices, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Robert R Blake and Jane Srygley Mouton
- Discussion Leadership Manual (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Education Intent of Policy, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Effective Speaking (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Employment Interview Assessing the Applicant (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Evaluating the Effectiveness of Laboratory Training in Industry (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Paul C Buchanan
- Evaluation form for Interviewers, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Spring Term 1961
- The Evolution and Revolution of the Teaching Machine, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Stanley L Levine and Leonard C Silvern. December 1960 - January 1961
- Executive Manpower Audit, Development and Control (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Exodus 18-13:23 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Fast-Changing Technology--Its Impact on Labor Problems, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  Richard C Wilcock
- Functions Relating to Manpower - Line or Staff, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Fall Term 1960
- The Fundamental Purpose for Training, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  April 14 1959
- General Areas of Industrial Training (Box 3, Folder 41)
- "George F's Happy Valley", 1962 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  Stephen Mahoney. September 1962
- Ghetto Youth See Right through Hypocrisy: 'No Gimmicks, please, Whitey', 1960 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  Kenneth B Clark. November 1960
- Grievance No. 57-12, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  ILR 461 Spring 1960
- Hourly Employee Induction Checklist, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Hourly Employee Induction Program (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Identifying Training Needs, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Identifying Training Needs from Appraisals--Basic Performance Factors, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- The Incident Process of Supervising Training: Case Study of Experience in a Small Plant, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  Donald M Marshall. September 1954
- The Role of Colleges and Universities in the Industrial Training Process, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  Dr. Robert F Risley
- The Interest Factors found in Various Jobs, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Is Training a Profession?, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  Gordon L Lippitt and Leslie This. April 1960
- Job Analysis Schedule--Electrician, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Job Analysis Schedule--Typist Clerk (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Job Description--Plant Personnel Manager, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  Fall 1957
- Job Breakdown Sheet (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Job Description--Training Director (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Job Instruction Training (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Training Within Industry: Job Instructor Training Check Sheet (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Lecture vs Group Decision in Changing Behavior, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  Jacob Levine and John Butler
- Learning About Learning (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Learning and the Instruction Process, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Learning Experiment Number Sheet, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Class Procedure--Learning Process Demonstration (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Life in the Automatic Factory, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  Charles R Walker
- Man Specifications, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  ILR 450. April 1 1967
- Management in the 1980's, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  Harold J Levitt and Thomas L Whistler
- The Management of Learning, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  Roger Bellows
- Management Promotion Policy, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  March 27 1968
- RCA "Manager and His Staff" Performance Goals Review Meetings (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Managerial or Supervisory Job (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Methods of Determining Training Needs, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 72)
- Muhlenberg Manufacturing Company Employee Performance Review Olan (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Muhlenberg Manufacturing Company Kingston Plant--Supervisory Training Survey (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Muhlenberg Manufacturing Company Production-Supervisor Training Program, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  Fall Term 1959
- No Room at the Top: The Problem of the "Average" Executive, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  W. R. G. Bender. July 1959
- New Union Frontier: White-Collar Workers, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Everett M Kassalow. January and February 1962
- The Organization Man Chapters 1 and 2, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  William A Whyte, Jr.
- Organizational Training Techniques, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Personnel Administration--A Chronology (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Personnel Journals in the ILR Library, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  ILR 450
- A Personnel Man Looks at the Case Method, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  A. Winn. May 1954
- Plan for Job Training Program (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pointing the Way to Better Human Relations through the Case Method, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Policies and Procedures governing Tuition Refund Plan, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  United States Gypsum Company and subsidiaries
- Principles of Learning, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- The Principles of Scientific Management, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- The Problem of change in the Advanced Industrial Economy of the United States, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  George H Hildebrand. October 5 - 6 1962
- The Process of Communication, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Programmed Instruction--What It is and Where It is Going, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Ned A Rosen and Emil a Mesics
- Programmed Learning, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Dr. Eugene H Fox
- Purposes of the Training Function at RCA, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Questionnaire--Labor Relations, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Range of Group Discussion Levels, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Case Incident No. A: The Reprimand Situation, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Research Concerning Barriers to Effective Two-Way Communication, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Frank W Braden and John T Trutter
- The Rich Grow Richer: Results of Studies Relating Development Readiness to Business Success, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Robert R Blake and Jane S Mouton. September 1966
- Sensitivity Training - What is It?, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Sensitivity Training in Business Organizations: Some Limitations (Box 4, Folder 24)
  John E Drotning
- Social Requirements of a Job, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Some Important Learning Principles, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Some Problems and Opportunities Facing Training Men, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Mr. F. W. Steckmest
- Some Problems of Adult Learning in the Work Environment, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Lawrence K Williams
- Chapter 1: Supervision or Leadership?, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  From "Leadership and Supervision" published by the US Civil Service Commission
- Supervisory Questionnaire, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Supervisory Training, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  ILR 431. April 11 1960
- Supervisory Training Survey, Department Managers, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Talking with your People: An Approach to Discussing a Man's Strengths and Weaknesses, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Team Job Training: A New Strategy for Industry, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Alvin C Bidwell. John J Farrell. Robert R Blake. Spring 1962
- Tests: Their Use and Misuse in Selection, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Herbert H Meyer. Joseph M Bertotti. May 1957
- Theory X: The Traditional View of Direction and Control, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Tips on Interviewing, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Tips for Troublesome Discussion Situations, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Training Needs of the New Engineer, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Policies and Procedures Governing Tuition Refund Plan, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Types of Temperamental Requirements Found in Various Jobs, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Esso Training Materials, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- General Electric Training Program, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Training Manual for Working Group Leaders in Leadership Techniques and Skills, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  Stephen Sworen. Summer 1955
- Economic Training, Technical Bulletins Nos. 22 and 40, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  Office of Industrial Resources, International Cooperation Administration
- Goodyear Office Management Conferences, 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Goodyear Factory Supervision Training, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Goodyear Supervision Training, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Supervision Training Conferences, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Linde Air Products Company, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  June 26 1957
- The Port of New York Authority, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Public Service Electric and Gas Company, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- The Seamen's Bank for Saving (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Sinclair Oil Corporation, 1946-1957 (Box 4, Folder 54)